A Few Days After the Battle of Arene
At Arene, I insisted on
defending my nation's people,
（ターニャ）アレーヌ市では
自国民保護の大義を守り―
直接的排除対象は
敵魔導師に徹底した
eliminating only the enemy mages.
いまだ私のお手々は
真っ白… のはず
My hands are still pure as
the driven snow... Probably.
（ウーガ）失礼する
（ターニャ）ん…
Excuse me.
It's been a long time, Major Degurechaff.
（ウーガ）
久しぶりだな デグレチャフ少佐
Üger...
ウーガ…
少佐殿 ご壮健で何よりです
Major Üger!
Glad to see you're doing well!
Same to you.
（ウーガ）
貴官も壮健そうで何よりだ
（ターニャ）
確か今は 陸軍鉄道部に？
You're with the army's
railway division now?
（ウーガ）ああ こちらでも
貴官の活躍は聞いている
Yes.
I've heard a lot about you.
それより これから参謀本部へ？
Anyway, are you on
your way to Strategic HQ?
Yes.
ええ 少佐殿も同じでしょうか？
You, too?
最近は ほとんど
ゼートゥーア閣下の使い走りだな
Lately, I've been doing nothing but
running errands for General Zettour...
鉄道部が大忙しということは…
大きな作戦でも？
If the railway division's busy,
then it's a big operation?
Looks like you know something.
何かご存じのようですね
Well, I guess it's safe to tell you.
まっ 貴官なら問題ないだろう
以前に後方勤務を
勧めてもらった恩義もあることだ
I owe you for recommending me
for a rearguard position.
The railway division has been asked to
現在 鉄道部には緊急戦域輸送の
計画が求められている
make a plan for emergency
transport from the combat zone.
The planning folks intend to
pull the Rhine front way back.
作戦局は ライン戦線を
大きく引っ込める腹らしい
（ターニャ）戦線を後退？
Pull back our lines?
ここまで押し返して
おきながらですか？
After we've pushed the
enemy so far back?
（ウーガ）そのとおり
Indeed.
敵の主力を引き込み
徹底的に たたく算段らしい
The plan seems to be to draw
the enemy's main unit in and destroy them.
I see.
（ターニャ）
なるほど ボナパルトの
アウステルリッツか―
So like Bonaparte at Austerlitz,
あるいは カンネーにおける
ハンニバルというわけか
or perhaps Hannibal at Cannae.
That's a surprise.
いやはや驚きました
ライン戦線ほどの規模で
包囲殲滅(せんめつ)戦とは
A surround-and-destroy operation
on the scale of the Rhine front...
A bold but fascinating plan.
大胆ですが 面白い発想です
（ウーガ）
まったくだ 上は何としても―
You've got that right.
The brass wants to end the war with
the Republic soon, no matter what.
共和国との戦争に
ケリをつけたいらしいな
（ターニャ）
しかし どのように敵の包囲を？
But how do we surround the enemy?
詳しくは知らされておらんが
I haven't been told the details.
But your unit will be asked
to serve as the rearguard
貴官の隊が後退を悟らせないための
殿軍に回されるらしい
so the enemy doesn't
learn about the retreat.
しんがり… ですか
The rearguard, huh?
これまで以上の
厳しい戦いになるはずだ
The battle will be even fiercer
than what's come before.
参謀本部に到着すれば
望むものは用意してくれるだろう
Once you get to Strategic HQ,
I'm sure they'll prepare
everything you ask for.
Imperial Army Strategic HQ, Joint Conference
The Arene incident damaged
our railway network,
（座長）
アレーヌ市の一件で―
鉄道網が傷つき
前線への補給状況は困窮
making supplying the front lines difficult.
A full-scale assault at this time
would be impossible to sustain.
現状での全面攻勢は
持続不可能かと
（参謀）協商連合同様 どこかに
上陸作戦を仕掛けるという構想は？
Is a landing operation possible,
like the one against the Entente Alliance?
（参謀長）
連合王国の対応が問題だ
The Allied Kingdom's response
would be the issue.
一応の中立を掲げてはいるが
In theory, they're neutral,
領海を突破されるとなれば
黙ってはいまい
but they won't let us pass through
their territorial waters.
（参謀）
となると やはり時間が…
Which means it will take time...
I believe some degree of
attrition is unavoidable.
（参謀）
多少の消耗は やむなしかと
We need a paradigm shift.
（ゼートゥーア）
パラダイムシフトが必要でしょう
We're facing the first world war
since the dawn of humanity.
（ゼートゥーア）
我々が直面しているのは
歴史が始まって以来の
世界大戦です
敵の城に攻め入って
“城下の盟(ちかい)”を結ばせるといった
The pre-war doctrine of entering an enemy
castle to force them to sign a peace treaty
戦前のドクトリンは
実現性が乏しすぎます
isn't practical here.
How do we win, then?
では どのように勝利を？
We don't win.
We avoid defeat.
勝利ではなく 敗北を避ける
I think that's the only way to stay standing.
これ以外に
最後まで立っているのは困難かと
General Zettour, are you saying
you're opposed to the offensive, too?
ゼートゥーア准将 つまり貴官も
攻勢案には反対というわけかね？
No, I support the idea
of aggressive action.
いえ 積極的な行動については
支持いたします
ただし その目的は
突破ではありません
But breaking their lines
shouldn't be our goal.
What do you mean?
と言うと？
We eliminate as many
enemy soldiers as possible
できるだけ多くの敵兵を
徹底して たたき
and render them unable
to continue fighting.
敵の戦争継続能力を粉砕する
That's the one way to end the war.
それが 戦争終結への唯一の道です
Do you have a practical plan?
（参謀長）具体案はあるのかね？
既に 作戦局が敵主力軍の
撃滅計画を立案済みです
The planning department already has
a plan to destroy their main force.
A decisive battle?
In these circumstances?
（参謀長）この状況で決戦を？
Are you serious?
（参謀）本気か？
（参謀）無謀では…
Isn't that reckless?
The first stage of this plan
is a large-scale withdrawal
（ルーデルドルフ）
本計画における第１作戦は
from the battle lines, in order
to lure the enemy forward.
戦線の大規模後退による敵の誘引
その後の作戦への布石であります
It's the first step toward the rest of the plan.
We must go forward.
我々は前に進まねばなりません
You could say a "forward escape"
is the best path toward victory.
いわば 前方への脱出こそ
最良の解決策であると
確信いたします
Episode Nine
Preparations for Advance
May 10, Unified Year 1925
Rhine Front: Imperial Army Right Flank, Front Lines
Break! Break!
（ターニャ）
ブレイク！ ブレイク！
（隊員）クソッタレ！ やられた！
Damn it! They got me!
03 カバーだ！
27を引きずって下がれ！
Take cover, 03!
Grab 27 and fall back!
（ノイマン）こちら04！
第４中隊 脱落者多数！
This is 04! Company 4
has lost multiple men!
損耗率 ６割以上！
Losses are at over 60%!
Company 4, put out decoys and retreat!
（ターニャ）第４中隊は
デコイを出しながら下がれ！
可能な者が援護しろ！
Anyone who can support them, do it!
Roger!
了解！
Who are our guests?
（共和国兵士）
侵入してきたお客さんは？
A force recon unit.
（共和国兵士）強行偵察隊だ
増強大隊規模だとよ！
They're the size of an expanded battalion!
Maybe they really are planning
a full-scale offensive!
連中が全面攻勢に出るってのも
いよいよ本気かもな
（共和国兵士）
来るぞ！ 撃て撃て撃てー！
They're coming! Fire! Fire!
（ケーニッヒ）
くっ！ 曳下(えいか)砲弾か！
Damn it! Air burst rounds?
Everyone, form up!
（ヴィーシャ）各員集中！
乱数回避機動を徹底し… はっ！
Limit yourself to stochastic evasion and—
This is 02!
（ヴァイス）
こちら02！ 既に半数が脱落！
We've lost half our men already!
We won't last much longer!
もう長くは もちません！
クソッ こちらフェアリー01
完全に包囲された上―
Damn...
This is Fairy 01!
We are surrounded and engaged with
a company-sized unit of enemy mages!
中隊規模の敵魔導部隊と交戦中！
そちらの状況は？
What is your situation?
Initiating Plan 1.
（通信兵）現在 第１作戦を実行中
Not quite ready yet,
完了まで あと少しだが
任務の即時中止許可は出ている
but you have permission for
an immediate withdrawal.
このタイミングで中止許可だと？
Permission to retreat? Now?
Unnecessary.
無用に願おう
（通信兵）何？ 本気か
What? Are you serious?
（ターニャ）ここで中止しては
欺瞞(ぎまん)行動の意図が露呈しかねん
If we retreat here,
they might discover our con.
戦線後退を敵に気づかれるわけには
いかない以上 続行する！
Since we can't let the enemy
learn about the retreat,
we will continue.
Roger.
（通信兵）了解した
できるかぎり急がせる
We'll have it ready ASAP.
May God's protection be with you.
貴官らに 神のご加護を
（ターニャ）“神のご加護”か…
God's protection...
I can see Being X's ugly face—
存在Ｘ(エックス)の いまいましい顔が
目に… はっ！
Rhine Front: Imperial Army Right Wing, Rawl Lowlands
（帝国兵士）早くしろー！
（帝国兵士）急げ！
（帝国兵士）重砲は破壊しろ！
Hurry!
Destroy the heavy cannons!
（帝国兵士）急げー！
The rest can get on the next train!
（帝国兵士）
残りは次だ！ 早く出せー！
Get moving!
Operation Fog and Sun
A False Retreat From the Battle Lines
We will shortly reach
the designated retreat point.
（帝国兵士）
間もなく後退の所定位置に到着
I don't see any pursuing forces.
敵の追撃部隊は見えない
They seem to think we're engaging
in a large-scale offensive.
こちらの大規模攻勢を
信じきっているようだ
（隊員）おいっ
（隊員）しっかりしろ！
Hey, hang in there!
（軍医）包帯が足りんぞ！
We don't have enough bandages!
（軍医）衛生魔導師は？
（軍医）まだか？
Where are the medic mages?
How much longer?
（タイヤネン）
は… 腹が… 腹が！
M-My stomach... My stomach!
（ノイマン）
准尉！ タイヤネン准尉！
Warrant Officer... Warrant Officer Teyanen!
Lieutenant Grantz, what were
your grades in classes?
グランツ少尉… 座学の成績は？
“部隊内での行為の責任は
全て部隊の指揮官にある”って
Didn't you learn in officers' school that
all responsibility for a unit's actions
将校課程で習わなかった？
法学の授業で
rests with their commanding officer?
In law class.
I think I did...
一応 習った気はしますが…
少佐殿は アレーヌ市の戦闘で
命令であることを強調された
At the Battle of Arene, the major emphasized
that you were acting under orders.
（ターニャ）もう一度だけ言う
これは上からの命令だ
I'll say this once more.
This is the order from our superiors.
指揮官は自分
だから部下が責任を負う必要はない
She was the commanding officer,
so there was no need for
her men to feel responsible.
ひょっとしたら
そんな意図があったのかもね
Maybe that's what she wanted to say.
（グランツ）まさか
セレブリャコーフ少尉に―
I never thought you'd be making me
feel better, Lieutenant Serebryakov.
慰められるとは
思いませんでしたよ
はあ？ 何それ！
Huh? What's that supposed to mean?
（ノイマン）
タイヤネン しっかりしろ！
Hang in there, Teyanen!
（タイヤネン）ああっ…
（ノイマン）タイヤネン！
Teyanen!
Plan 1 was a success.
（レルゲン）第１作戦は無事完了
（レルゲン）
全ては貴官の隊のおかげだ
It's all thanks to your unit.
On behalf of Strategic HQ,
I thank you again.
参謀本部を代表し
改めて礼を言おう
Your words honor me too much.
（ターニャ）
身に余るお言葉 感謝いたします
Actually, I wanted to ask you something.
そんな中 恐縮ですが
１つお尋ねしたいことがありまして
What is it?
（レルゲン）何か？
I'm told our military is distributing
false propaganda via third countries?
現在 我が軍は第三国を通じて
偽のプロパガンダを
流布しているそうですね
You hear things fast.
さすがに 耳が早いな
Supposedly, the mess at Arene
destroyed our supply lines.
（ターニャ）いわく―
我々はアレーヌ市のゴタゴタで
補給線が崩壊
Even maintaining our front is difficult,
もはや前線維持も
危ぶまれる状況の中―
and we're planning a reckless,
large-scale assault.
無謀な大規模攻勢を
計画していると
"The Empire on the Brink"
それを信じた共和国軍は
兵力を集中させるでしょう
Republican forces will believe it
and will concentrate their forces.
A Desperate Large-Scale Assault?
その主力軍を引き込んで
包囲殲滅するには―
If we want to draw them in,
encircle them, and wipe them out,
敵兵の統制を乱し
混乱させる必要があるのでは？
don't we need to disrupt them
and put them in disarray?
Just like at Norden?
ノルデンの時と同じか…
まったく 貴官という存在は…
You never cease to amaze me...
Your new orders.
新たな作戦の指示書だ
Thank you.
拝見いたします
The name of the second
operation is "Shock and Awe."
第２作戦名は“衝撃と畏怖”
The plan is to directly take
out the enemy's HQ
その内容は 敵司令部を
直接たたく衝撃によって―
and leave them in disarray.
敵を混乱に導くことにある
And then capture the enemy units?
やはり 敵主力の遊兵化を？
いかにも
Indeed.
（ターニャ）なるほど
戦略レベルでは大いに道理かと
I see.
On a strategic level,
it makes a good deal of sense.
But if it were that easy to
take out the enemy's HQ,
ですが 敵の司令部を容易に
たたけるならば―
そもそも ライン戦線は
膠着(こうちゃく)などしないはずでは？
the Rhine theater wouldn't have
fallen into a stalemate to begin with.
That is quite true.
確かに そのとおりだな
Then we'll need a new tactic.
では 第２作戦遂行のためには
常識を超えた新たな戦術が必要…
Something completely unexpected.
（シューゲル）バーン！
（ターニャ）いっ!?
（シューゲル）これも
神のお導きであられるな 少佐！
God has brought us to this moment, hasn't he, Major?
Doctor Schugel?
ドクトル… シューゲル!?
Imperial Army V-1 Launcher Secret Base
What is this?
（ターニャ）
何なのだ これは…
（シューゲル）私が開発した
強行偵察用の特殊追加加速装置―
A special acceleration booster device
I developed for force recon.
秘匿呼称“Ｖ－１(ブイワン)”だよ
Code named V-1!
It's a new type of recon unit
（レルゲン）
迎撃不可能な高高度を―
that flies too high to be intercepted
and too fast to be pursued.
追尾不能な速度で飛しょうする
新型の偵察機材だ
Use these V-1s to cross their
defensive lines and attack their HQ.
このＶ－１で 敵防衛線を飛び越え
司令部を強襲してもらう
When did you build this?
（ターニャ）
いつの間に こんな物を…
ゼートゥーア閣下の要請で
進めていた
General Zettour requested
their development.
He requested a new type of equipment
to break through heavily defended areas.
重防御陣地を突破する
新装備の開発を技術省へ要求し…
どこかの狂信的な科学者が―
And a certain mad scientist made something
that surpassed your expectations, huh?
予想以上の物を
作り上げたわけですか
（レルゲン）
まだ性能テストの段階だったが―
It's still in the testing stages,
but the fact that we could get a small run
共和国との決戦を前に―
of mass-produced versions ready
before the decisive battle is truly...
低率量産型が
間に合ったことは まさに…
（シューゲル）まさに福音！
Truly, a blessed message from God!
福音としか
言いようがないであろう！
That's the only way to describe it!
見たまえ！
この大型ブースターを！
Behold these huge boosters!
ヒドラジン燃料を使用する特注品を
５基も搭載しておるのだぞ！
It contains five specially-made
engines that run on hydrogen fuel!
Doctor, it's fine to boast
about their size and numbers,
ドクトル… 大きさと数を
誇るのは結構ですが
速度や方向の調整は
できるのでしょうね？
but you can adjust their
speed and direction, right?
調整？ そんなものは必要ない！
ただ まっすぐ飛べばよい
Adjustments?
You don't need adjustments!
Just fly straight!
ただ まっすぐ
進み続ければよいのだ！
Just keep going straight forward!
（シューゲル）ん？ その顔…
That look on your face...
ブースターが重すぎるのでは
ないかと心配しているのだな？
You're worried the boosters
might be too heavy, right?
Relax! No need to worry at all!
案ずるな！ 心配は要らん！
The used fuel tanks can be purged from
the booster when they're empty.
これらの噴射口は 空になった
燃料タンクと切り離すことが可能！
機体を軽量化することで
最終的な速度が さらに高まるのだ
By lightening the load,
the final speed gets even higher!
（シューゲル）
その最高速度は マッハ1,5！
Its final speed is Mach 1.5!
人類史上初の超音速によって
一切合財を…
As the first humans to
break the sound barrier,
we will shake off anyone
and everyone on our tail!
一切合財を振り切るのだあ！
Um, how will you handle the increase
あのう… 音速を超えたことによる
造波抗力の急増や衝撃波の対策は…
in drag and shock waves caused
by breaking the sound barrier?
空力弾性による振動や衝撃は
魔導師の防殻で対処できるはずだ
Vibrations and shocks caused
by aeroelastic flutter
should be something mages can
handle with their defensive shell.
できるであろう？
できなければ おかしい
You can do it, right?
It would be strange if you couldn't.
I suppose he thinks everything
comes naturally to everyone.
まさしく… 天才だな
Yeah. He's a natural-born disaster.
ええ… 天の災いです
He went and got us a
one-way ticket to hell.
片道切符で地獄行きの代物ですよ
Rhine Front: Former Imperial Army Right Wing, Rawl Lowlands
No response.
（偵察兵）反応ありません！
やはり完全に撤退したようです
It seems they really have withdrawn.
Roger.
（指揮官）
了解 司令部につなぐ
Contact command.
This is Rhine Command,
（通信兵）
ライン方面 司令部より―
speaking to all units on the left flank.
Republican Army Rhine Theater Forces
戦線左翼に展開中の
全部隊に告ぐ
We have confirmed that Imperial forces
have withdrawn from the Rawl Lowlands.
（通信兵）ロール低地における
帝国軍の撤退を確認
Rhine Theater: Republican Army Left Wing, Rear Echelon
現刻をもって
主力部隊の前進を開始せよ
Begin advancing our main force immediately.
Roger.
（通信兵）了解
All units, advance!
（指揮官）全隊 進めえー！
We've gathered our main forces
and started advancing the left flank.
（ビアント）
我が軍は主力部隊を結集し―
前線左翼の押し上げを
開始しました
The right flank is staying put.
（ビアント）右翼については
依然として停滞中でありますが―
If we take out the left flank,
the Empire will give up.
左翼さえ突破すれば
帝国軍も音を上げるでしょう
And that will end the war, huh?
（ド･ルーゴ）
これで ケリがつくわけか
ええ 私もアレーヌでの
借りを返したいところですが
Yes.
I want to repay them for
what happened in Arene.
But I'm reduced to
a cigarette gofer for a while...
当分はタバコ犬役でして
Distribute them among the right flank.
They aren't doing anything.
（ド･ルーゴ）
暇な右翼にでも渡してやれ
Are you sure?
よろしいのですか？
Leave enough to celebrate our victory.
戦勝記念の祝杯分は残しておけよ
Second Lieutenant Grantz.
（ヴァイス）グランツ少尉
Lieutenant Weiss...
（グランツ）ヴァイス中尉殿…
Calm down, Lieutenant.
（ヴァイス）落ち着け 少尉
さすがに みっともないぞ
You look kind of pathetic.
（グランツ）すみません 中尉
Sorry, sir.
まあ 気持ちは分かる
Well, I understand how you feel.
To be honest, I don't feel calm, either.
自分も正直 落ち着かないよ
Now, you've been specially
selected for this mission.
（ターニャ）さて 選抜中隊の諸君
言葉を飾らずに言えば
今回の任務は―
To be blunt,
our mission is to ride rockets
right into the enemy HQ.
人間ロケットで敵司令部に
突っ込めというわけだ
I'm sure that only a few of you eleven
are capable of enjoying a rocket ride,
貴官ら 11名の中に
ロケットでの投射を楽しめる者は
数少ないと思われるが
but we have to do this.
やるしかない
And if we have to do it,
we must ensure we succeed.
やるしかないのであれば
成功させねばならない！
事前情報を基にした
襲撃の対象は３か所
Our current intelligence has
given us three attack targets.
One of them is the
enemy's Rhine theater HQ.
いずれかが 敵の
ライン方面司令部と目される
Once we take it out, the enemy will
be leaderless and easily destroyed.
ここを刈り取ってしまえば
頭のない軍隊など鎧袖一触(がいしゅういっしょく)だ
In other words, tomorrow's
mission will end the war!
つまり 明日の作戦こそが
戦争を終わらせる一撃だ！
We are the head of the entire army!
我々は全軍の先鋒(せんぽう)たるぞ！
No soldier in the Empire
could remain calm after that.
これで落ち着いていられる軍人など
帝国はおろか 世界のどこにも…
Hell, no soldier in the world could.
前言撤回だな…
I take that back.
The Republic's main force has
already started its advance.
（報告兵）
既に 共和国軍主力は前進を開始
Only a matter of time before the western
industrial districts are within firing range.
西方の重工業地帯を
射程圏内におさめるのも―
時間の問題かと
Preparations for Plan 2, the assault
on the enemy HQ, are ready.
第２作戦 敵司令部強襲の
準備は整った
What is the state of the next plan?
次なる作戦状況は？
I'm told we're finishing our last
preparations on the left flank.
（報告兵）
前線左翼にて最終作業中とのこと
Deployments at the target
point are completed,
目標地点への設置も完了し
明日にも決行できるとの報告です
and we can begin tomorrow.
既に ルビコンは越えた
We've crossed the Rubicon.
And now, it's all up to
Major Degurechaff, huh?
あとは デグレチャフ少佐に
懸かっているわけか
我々が黙って食事とは…
If we're eating in silence, we must
be more nervous than I expected.
存外 緊張しているらしいな
フンッ お前は緊張と無縁かと
思っていたが
I thought you never got nervous.
You, too.
（ゼートゥーア）
お互い様だろう 私こそ―
I'm surprised to find you're nervous.
お前が緊張するということに
驚いている
The Fatherland's fate
rests on this mission.
祖国の命運を懸けた計画だ
If we fail to take the enemy's head,
the remaining plans will also fail.
敵の頭を刈り取り損ねれば
残りの作戦も ご破算だ
前に出るしか 帝国に活路はない
Moving forward is the
only way we can win.
No, it's the only path we have at all.
否 前進するしか道はないのだ
祖国の前に立ちふさがるものは
全て打ち破ってみせよう
Anyone who stands in the way of
the Fatherland will be destroyed.
My friend, victory for the Empire!
友よ 帝国に勝利を！
Victory!
勝利を
May 25, Unified Year 1925
（技師）ヒドラジン燃料の
充填(じゅうてん) 確認
Hydrogen fuel levels confirmed.
（技師）
射点および 投射角度の調整よし！
Firing angle and direction confirmed!
All equipment working normally.
（技師）全装置 正常に起動
All units, proceed to final preparations.
各機 最終準備に入りたまえ
Releasing safeties.
（技師）安全装置 解除
Launch preparations complete.
（技師）
投射準備 完了しました
Staff is to leave the area!
（技師）作業員 退避！
We will now launch a mage company
（レルゲン）
これより 人力誘導式噴進弾―
via the manned rockets code named V-1!
秘匿呼称 Ｖ－１による
魔導中隊の投射を行う
各機 点火
Light all rockets.
May God watch over the Fatherland.
（シューゲル）
祖国に神のご加護があらんことを
My comrades-in-arms, I believe not in God,
（ターニャ）戦友諸君
私は神ではなく参謀本部を…
論理と知性の牙城を信ずる
but in Strategic HQ,
a stronghold of logic and reason.
義務と献身こそが我らの誉れだ
Our pride lies in duty and sacrifice.
We go to win this battle.
この戦い 勝ちにいくぞ！
A true Imperial soldier goes anywhere,
even Purgatory, and conquers it!
煉獄(れんごく)であろうと赴き
征服することこそ 帝国軍人の本務
kogoeru you ni hosoi karada o furuwaseru
My body shakes, as if it were freezing
Show them what good
guard dogs we are!
番犬は優秀であるということを
教えてやれ！
All units, take off.
全機 発進！
kyoufu kara de wa naku shizuka na netsujou
Not from fear, but from a silent fervor
todoroku tsuyoi kaze ni himei sae kakikiete wa
The roaring wind drowns out even screams
shouen mau sora ni yume o miru darou
In a sky filled with gunpowder smoke, I'll surely witness a dream
I shall pray for your success.
成功を祈る
kanashisa mo sabishisa mo kanjiru koto wa naku
I don't feel sadness, or loneliness
I was supposed to climb the
ladder in the rear lines.
安全な後方で出世するはずが
どうして…
How did I end up here?
mata hitotsu hone ga kawaku
My bones just feel even more dry
oo aijou, retsujou, subete mujou
Ohh, love... lust... all things cruel!
It's all... It's all Being X's fault.
（ターニャ）
全ては… 全ては存在Ｘのせいだ
sono migoto sugu honoo ni moete hai ni naru
Your form will be thrust into the flame, reduced to ash
あのクソッタレに市場原理を
たたき込むまでは―
Until I pound free-market
principles into that piece of shit,
I won't die, no matter what!
何があろうと
死ぬわけにはいかない！
outou se yo, outou se yo, kagayakeru mirai yo
Please respond... please respond... hear my call, shining future!
I'm going to live... to live and...
生きて絶対に 絶対に…
終わらせる！
I'm going to end this!
Everyone, prepare for
non-magic-dependent drop!
（ターニャ）
各員 非魔導依存降下だ！
ima, me no sameru you na riaru o
Right now, I'll offer an eye opening reality
ドアノッカー分離！
Release door knockers!
kono iyou naru yo ni sasageyou
Unto this bizarre world
Operation Shock and Awe
Assault on the Enemy HQ
"To the family of my friend,
Warrant Officer Tweet Nika Teyanen.
I'm terribly sorry to inform you
that Warrant Officer Teyanen
will be retiring due to injuries.
A military doctor has decided
that he needs long-term care.
I ask forgiveness that I can only return
the child you entrusted to us in this state.
I know it isn't much,
but I have put in a request
for a Class 1 Combat Medal
and a War Injuries Medal,
and it has been accepted.
I hope he successfully recovers."
I never thought I'd lose one of
my troops to a rotten potato...
Next Episode
Path to Victory
（ターニャ）
“拝啓 親愛なる―”
“ツイーテ･ナイカ･
タイヤネン准尉の ご家族様”
“この度 誠に残念ながら―”
“タイヤネン准尉の傷痍(しょうい)退役を
ご報告させていただきます”
“彼は軍医の診断によって―”
“長期の療養が必要と
判断されました”
“お預かりした お子様を―”
“このような形でしか
お返しできないことを―”
“ご容赦ください”
“わずかばかりの
慰めになることを願って―”
“小官の名で
１級野戦従軍章と―”
“傷痍メダルを申請し
認められました”
“彼の闘病と回復を
祈念しております”
（ターニャ）ハァ…
まさか 腐ったジャガイモで―
部下を失うことになるとはなあ…
（ターニャ）ハァ…